Two countries, two loves, one heart
Brooklyn is a romance, drama, history film directed by John Crowley.
In 1950s Ireland and New York, young Eilis Lacey has to
choose between two men and two countries.
Eilis Lacey, played by Saoirse Ronan.
Jim Farrell, played by Domhnall Gleeson.
Tony Fiorello, played by Emory Cohen.
Father Flood, played by Jim Broadbent.
Madge Kehoe, played by Julie Walters.
Miss Fortini, played by Jessica Paré.
Brooklyn is a 2015 romantic period drama film directed by John Crowley and
written by Nick Hornby, based on the 2009 novel by Colm Tóibín.
A co-production between the United Kingdom, Ireland, and Canada, it stars Saoirse Ronan in the lead role,
with Emory Cohen, Domhnall Gleeson, Jim Broadbent, and Julie Walters in supporting roles.
The plot follows Eilis Lacey, a young Irish woman who migrates to
Brooklyn in the early 1950s to find employment.
After building a life there, she is drawn back to her home town of
Enniscorthy and has to choose where she wants to forge her future.
Principal photography began in April 2014 with three weeks of filming in Ireland, which were followed by four weeks in Montreal,
Quebec; only two days of filming took place in Brooklyn, one of which was spent at the beach in Coney Island.
The film premiered on 26 January 2015 at the Sundance Film Festival, and was later screened as part of the
Special Presentations section of the Toronto International Film Festival on 13 September.
It opened in the United States on 4 November, in the United Kingdom
and Ireland on 6 November and in Canada on 20 November.
Critical response to the film was overwhelmingly positive, with
many reviewers praising the screenplay and direction.
Ronan's performance was also highlighted by many critics, and she was nominated for numerous awards for Best
Actress, including a BAFTA, Critics' Choice Award, Golden Globe, and Screen Actors Guild Award.
The film won the BAFTA Award for Best British Film, and was nominated for three Academy
Awards: Best Picture, Best Actress (for Ronan), and Best Adapted Screenplay.
It was also featured on more than 120 film critics' "Top 10" lists of the best films of 2015, and
was ranked 48th on the BBC's 2016 list of the 100 Greatest Films of the 21st Century.
The film explores themes of ship, based on novel or book,
love triangle, homesickness, marriage.
The tone is emotional.